#### SALAKO TOYIBAT A.

Email: toyibatsalakoa@gmail.com Phone: 08071514229/09096684575 Address: Ijebu-Ode, Ogun State, Nigeria.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/toyibat-salako-ab166026a

A UI/UX Designer who specializes in User Research, User Centered Design, User Experience, Prototyping, and Design Thinking and has an eye for good design and colour combination. I also have basic knowledge in Front-end Development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. A first Class Graduate of Islamic Studies Education (B.A. Ed.) at Tai Solarin University of Education, Ogun State, Nigeria. I have great leadership, follower-ship, collaboration and teamwork spirit.

## **SKILLS**

- User Interface (UI) / User Experience (UX) and User Centred Design
- Wire-framing and Prototyping
- User Research, Usability Testing and Product Management
- HTML/CSS
- Teamwork and Time Management
- Creative Thinking and Problem Solving
- Leadership and Interpersonal Relationship

## **EDUCATION**

Oct. 2023 - Present

## ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

 <b>Q</b> 011221110110110

Product Design (UI/UX)

Tech4Dev

Women Techsters Fellowship Class of 2024

Sept. 2023 - Nov. 2023 Postgraduate Diploma (PGD)

Postgraduate Diploma (PGD), Human Resource Management. International College of Safety and Management Professional (ICSMP)

Sept. 2017 - Nov. 2021 B.A. Ed. Islamic Studies

Tai Solarin University of Education, Ijagun, Ogun State, Nigeria. Department of Religious Studies (Islamic Studies Unit)

First Class Honors Division

GPA 4 64/5 0

Sept. 2011 - Aug. 2017 Secondary School

Tai Solarin University of Education Secondary School (TASUESS)

Ijebu-Ode, Ogun State, Nigeria.

Date of Graduation: 15th August, 2017.

Sept. 2004 - July 2011

# **Primary School**

Tai Solarin College of Education (TASCE) Staff School Igbegba,

Ijebu-Ode, Ogun State, Nigeria.

Date of Graduation: 26th July, 2011.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

1. Certified UI/UX Designer at CWW Tech Africa Training Program (Cohort 4.0). August 2023

2. Human Resource Management Certificate at Great Learning Academy. April 2024

3. UI/UX for Beginners Certificate at Great Learning Academy. April 2024

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

1. Certified Compensation and Benefit Professional (CCBP)	November 2023
2. Certified Training and Development Professional (CTDP)	November 2023
3. Human Resource Management Professional (HRMP)	November 2023

# MEMBERSHIP AND AFFILIATIONS

Sept. 2023 - Present	Associate, International Chattered for Human Resource Management, AICHRM, (ICSP007088)
Jan. 2023 - Present	Member, Education Community Development Group (CDS), National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Ife Central Local Government, Ile-Ife, Osun State Nigeria.
Nov. 2022 - Present	Member Muslim Corpers Association of Nigeria (MCAN) Osun State, Nigeria.
Feb. 2022 - Present	Member Tai Solarin Muslim Alumni Association.
Feb. 2022 - Present	Alumni Member of Tai Solarin University of Education, Ijagun, Ogun State, Nigeria.
2017 - Present	Member, Islamic Studies Students Association of Nigeria. (ISSAN) (TASUED Branch)
2017 - Present	Member, Muslim Students Society of Nigeria (MSSN) (TASUED Branch).
2011 - 2014	Member, Girls in Science Project.
2009 - 2011	Member, Young Readers Club.

## **JOB EXPERIENCE**

Jan 2023 - Nov. 2023 National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)

## Administrative Staff (OAU, IFEDS, Osun State Nigeria.)

• Worked as an Admin Staff at Obafemi Awolowo University (OAU) at the Institute For Entrepreneurship and Development Studies (IFEDS).

# March 2021 - July 2021 Teaching Practice (TP) exercise 2020/2021 session.

Tai Solarin University of Education Staff School Igbegba, Ijebu- Ode.

• Taught Junior and Senior Secondary School students Islamic Religious Studies at Tai Solarin University of Education Secondary School, Ijebu-Ode, Ogun State, Nigeria.

## **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

- Organized and carried out an Educational outreach in Ife Girls High School during my NYSC at Osun State Nigeria for my Education CDS Group. **October**, **2023**.
- Organized and carried out Tech Girls Drive to enlighten girls about tech in celebration of Women's Month at Adeola Odutola College, Ogun State Nigeria with my group members at Tech4Dev Women Techsters Programme (Class of 2024). March, 2024.

## ACHIEVEMENTS (HONORS AND AWARDS)

•	2023	President Education Community Development Service (CDS) Group during NYSC at Osun State, Nigeria.
•	2022	First Class Honors in Islamic Studies Education (B.A. Ed.)
•	2017	Mosque Prefect Award in Secondary School (TASUESS) 2016/2017 set.
•	2017	Price for Best Student in Islamic Religious Studies (IRS) in SS3
		(TASUESS) by Alhaji Tunde Oduwole 2016/2017 set.
•	2015 - 2017	Award of the Principal (Principal's Price) for well-behaved student
		(TASUESS) three consecutive times. 2014/2015, 2015/2016 and
		2016/2017 set.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Journal Publication**

Asif Olatubosun Azeez and Toyibat Adeola Salako (2022). Perception of People in Ijebu-Ode on Islamic Banking and Finance: Al-Hayat Microfinance Bank Limited in Focus. Journal of the Nigeria Association of Teachers of Arabic and Islamic Studies (NATAIS). Ad-Daliil - NATAIS Ogun State Chapter, Volume 2 Number 1, June 2022, Pg 62-86. <a href="https://nataisogun.com/ad-daliil">https://nataisogun.com/ad-daliil</a>.

### LANGUAGES

English: Native language, Proficient in listening, speaking, reading and writing. Yoruba: Native language, Proficient in listening, speaking, reading and writing.

### REFERENCES

• Available Upon Request.